你受伤了?
我来帮你吧
谢谢你
你叫什么名字?
我叫Claudia
真是个好名字
That's a lovely name.
这儿没别人了吗?
Where are the rest of your people?
就只有我一个
There's only me.
你怎么到这儿来的?
How did you get here?
和你一样...
The same way you got here...
纯属意外
By accident.
- 你来了多久... - 问题太多了
- How long have you... - Every question I answer
问完一个又一个
will simply lead to another question.
你应该好好休息 能活下来就是万幸
You should rest. Just be grateful you're alive.
- 我船上还有人呢 我得去... - 不
- There were other people on my ship. I need to go... - No.
如果岛上还有别人 我肯定能找到
If there are other people on the island, I will find them.
要生了吗?
The baby?
哦!
Oh!
我要生了
It's coming.
就是这样
That's it.
用劲! 再加把劲!
Push! Push harder.
我生不下来!
I can't!
不 你可以的
Yes, you can.
就是这样!
That's good!
再加把劲
One more push.
哦! 哦!
Oh! Oh!
是个儿子哦
It's a boy.
名字我取好了 叫Jacob
His name is Jacob.
是个儿子呢
It's a boy.
我能不能...
Can I...
还有一个孩子
There's another baby.
啊!
Aah!
加把劲
Push again.
快出来了
Here it comes.
用劲啊!
Now!
哦!
Oh!
又是个儿子
It's another boy.
我只想好了一个名字
I only picked one name.
哦 嘘 嘘
Oh. Shh. Shh.
我能瞧瞧他么?
May I see him?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
啊!
Uhh!
啊! 啊!
Uhh! Uhh!
迷失 第6季第15集
这是什么?
What is it?
是个游戏棋
It's a game.
拿来玩的
You play it.
你怎么会玩呢?
How do you know how?
我就是会呗
I just know.
你能教我玩么?
Will you show me how to play?
如果你答应不告诉妈妈 我就教你玩
If you promise not to tell mother.
为什么不能告诉她?
Why can't we tell her?
因为她会把这东西没收掉
Because she'll take it away.
那... 你到底想不想玩 Jacob?
So... do you wanna play or don't you, Jacob?
嗯 我想玩
Yes. I wanna play.
你好 Jacob
Hello, Jacob.
你好 妈妈
Hello, mother.
你弟弟在哪儿?
Where's your brother?
他在海滩那边...
He's down at the beach...
眺望大海
staring out at the ocean.
需要我帮忙吗?
Can I help you?
如果你愿意的话 就帮我把那些线分开来
If you like, you can sort that.
你和弟弟到海滩那儿干嘛呢?
What were you and your brother doing down at the beach?
我们只是... 散散步而已
We were just... walking.
你爱我吗 Jacob?
Do you love me, Jacob?
爱
Yes.
那就把事实告诉我
Then tell me what happened.
我可以坐这儿吗?
May I join you?
当然可以
Sure.
Jacob把我找到的东西 告诉你了
Jacob told you what I found.
没错
Of course he did.
Jacob不会撒谎
Jacob doesn't know how to lie.
他可不像你这样
He's not like you.
什么意思? 我什么样儿?
Why? What am I like?
你...
You're...
很特别
special.
我能继续留着这个游戏棋么?
Can I keep the game?
当然可以
Of course you can.
所以我才把它给你啊
That's why I left it for you.
它是你的?
It came from you?
嗯 不然它还能是谁的?
Of course it did. Where else would it come from?
从大海那头的
From somewhere else.
某个地方飘过来的
Across the sea.
不可能的
There is nowhere else.
这个岛是唯一的陆地
The island is all there is.
那我们是从哪儿来的?
Then where did we come from?
你和你哥哥是我生的
You and your brother came from me,
我又是我妈妈生的
and I came from my mother.
那她在哪儿?
Where is she?
她去世了
She's dead.
什么叫"去世"?
What's "dead"?
这事 你永远不必担心
Something you will never have to worry about.
快! 它跑了!
Hurry up! He's getting away!
快藏起来!
Hide!
- 他们是谁? - 嘘!
- Who are they? - Shh!
妈妈!
Mother!
怎么了?
What's wrong?
有人来了 我们看到几个男人
We saw people. Men.
- 他们有多少人? - 三个 他们杀了头野猪
- How many were there? - Three. They killed a boar.
他们看到你们了吗?
Did they see you?
没有
No.
我想没有吧
I don't think so.
他们从什么地方来的? 他们看起来跟我们好像
Where did they come from? They looked like us.
他们跟我们不一样
They're not like us.
他们不是这儿的
They don't belong here.
我们来这儿是有原因的
We are here for a reason.
什么原因?
What reason?
现在还不是说的时候
It's not time yet.
妈妈 是什么原因啊?
Mother, what reason?
跟我来
Come with me.
- 你认识这些人吗? - 认识
- Did you know about the people? - Yes.
你怎么没和我们提起过他们?
Why didn't you tell us about them?
因为他们很危险 我不想让你们担惊受怕
Because they're dangerous, and I didn't want to frighten you.
他们怎么就危险了呢?
What makes them dangerous?
所有人都因此而危险
The same thing that makes all men dangerous.
先来 后斗 接着毁灭 最后沦落
They come. They fight. They destroy. They corrupt.
结局总是相同的
And it always ends the same.
- 他们"来"? 从哪儿来? - 从岛上的另一个地方来
- They "come"? Come from where? - Another part of the island.
你们千万不要去找他们
And you're never to go looking for them.
如果他们发现了你们 他们会伤害你们的
If they found you, they would hurt you.
他们会什么要伤害我们?
Why would they hurt us?
因为他们是人 Jacob 是人就会那么做
Because they're people, Jacob, and that's what people do.
但我们也是人啊 照你这么说 我们也会互相伤害喽?
But we're people. Does that mean that we can hurt each other?
我不会让你们互相伤害的
I've made it so you can never hurt each other.
这是什么地方?
What is this place?
这就是我们来这儿的原因
This is the reason we're here.
不要进去
Don't go in there.
下面是什么东西?
What's down there?
光
Light.
最温暖
The warmest,
最明亮的光
brightest light
是你不曾看见或感觉过的
you've ever seen or felt.
我们必须确保没人能找到它
And we must make sure that no one ever finds it.
太美了
It's beautiful.
是啊
Yes, it is.
这就是他们想得到它的原因
And that's why they want it,
因为每个人的心中
because a little bit of this very same light
都有一点这种光
is inside of every man.
但是他们贪得无厌
But they always want more.
他们能拿得到吗?
Can they take it?
拿不到 但他们会去试
No, but they would try.
一旦试过 他们就会把它带出去
And if they tried, they could put it out.
如果光从这儿被带出去了...
And if the light goes out here...
那就会变得到处都是了
it goes out everywhere.
所以我守护着这个地方
And so I've protected this place,
但我无法永远守护这里
but I can't protect it forever.
那还有谁可以呢?
Then who will?
将会是你们中的一个
It will have to be one of you.
- 你不能这么走 Jacob - 为什么不能?
- You can't do that, Jacob. - Why not?
因为这是违反规则的
Because it's against the rules.
- 规则是你定的 - 这东西是我找到的
- You made the rules. - I found it.
哪天 你要是自己新创了一个游戏
One day, you can make up your own game,
那其他人都得按你定的规则来
and everyone else will have to follow your rules.
没关系
It's all right.
不要害怕
Don't be afraid.
怎么了?
What?
What's wrong?
我去海滩上散会儿步
I'm going for a walk to the beach.
过会儿我来找你
I'll meet you late
你好
Hello.
Jacob为什么看不见你?
Why can't Jacob see you?
因为我已经死了
Because I'm dead.
想跟我来吗? 我给你看点儿东西
Will you come with me? I'd like to show you something.
给我看什么?
Show me what?
你的出生地
Where you came from.
在岛的另外一端... 你从来没见过的地方
It's across the island... a place you've never seen.
他们是谁?
Who are they?
13年前他们来到了这儿...
They came here 13 years ago...
就在你出生的前一天
The day before you were born.
他们的船在一场暴风中失事了
Their ship was wrecked in a storm.
船是什么东西?
Ship. What's that?
人们乘坐它 从一个地方去往另一个地方
It's a way for people to get from one place to another.
我们就是乘坐它漂洋过海的
It's how we came across the sea.
但海外并没有东西啊
But there's nothing across the sea.
海外有很多东西
There are many things across the sea.
你也是越洋而来的
You come from across the sea, too.
不 不是那样的
No. That's not true.
我妈妈不是这么跟我说的
That's not what my mother told me.
她不是你的妈妈
She's not your mother.
我才是
I am.
Jacob啊
Jacob.
Jacob 醒醒
Jacob, wake up.
跟我来
Come with me.
你为什么把你的东西都带在身上啊?
Why do you have all your things?
那是我们的东西
They're our things.
我带着它们 是因为我们要走了
I took them because we're leaving,
- 我们再也不回来了 - 什么?
- and we're never coming back. - What?
跟我走就是了
Just follow me.
跟你去哪儿?
Follow you where?
去他们那儿
To the people.
不 我们应该远离他们
No. We're supposed to stay away from them.
那是我们的人 Jacob 我们要和他们一起生活
They're our people, Jacob, and we're gonna live with them.
不 妈妈说...
No, mother said...
她骗你的 所有这些... 都是她骗你的
She lied. She lied about everything... all of it.
我知道你无法理解 但你必须得跟我我走
I know you don't understand, but you have to come with me.
- 我不想一个人去 - 不行 妈妈爱我们
- I don't want to go by myself. - We can't. Mother loves us.
- 她根本不爱我们 - 住口!
- She doesn't love us. - Stop!
- 这都是谎言! - 住口!
- It was all a lie! - Stop it!
- 她都根本不是我们的妈妈! - 啊!
- She's not even our mother! - Aah!
- 不是的! - Jacob!
- No! - Jacob!
- 你这是干什么? - 他要离开这里!
- What are you doing? - He's leaving!
他要去和他们在一起!
He's going to them!
和那些人一起!
To the other people!
什么?
What?
我都知道了
I know now.
海的那边还有一片天地
There is another place across the sea.
我是从那儿来的
It's where I'm from,
所以我要回到那儿去 我要回家
and I'm gonna go there. I'm gonna go home.
谁... 是谁告诉你这些的?
Who... who told you that?
我妈妈!
My mother!
我就是你妈妈
I'm your mother.
是你杀了我母亲
You killed my mother.
Jacob啊...
Jacob...
那也是你的母亲
She was your mother, too.
我们不属于这里 也不属于她
We don't belong here. We don't belong with her.
跟我一起走吧
Come with me.
我不走
No.
亲爱的 你得知道
My love, you need to know this.
无论你听说了什么
Whatever you have been told,
你永远都不能离开这座岛
you will never be able to leave this island.
我不信
That's not true.
总有一天 我会证明给你看的
And one day, I can prove it.
你认为他还会回来吗?
Do you think he'll come back?
不会
No.
他说 你杀了我们的妈妈
He said you killed our mother.
是真的吗?
Is that true?
没错
Yes.
如果我不杀她
If I had let her live,
她就会带着你们 回到她那儿去
she would have taken you back to her people,
那些人都是坏人 Jacob... 坏透了
and those people are bad, Jacob... very bad.
我... 我不能让你们和他们同流合污
I... I couldn't let you become one of them.
我要你们成为好人
I needed you to stay good.
我是好人吗 妈妈?
Am I good, mother?
是的 当然是
Yes. Of course you are.
那为什么你更爱他一些呢?
Then why do you love him more than me?
我爱你 只是... 方式不同
I love you in... in different ways.
你会待在我身边吗 Jacob?
Will you stay with me, Jacob?
求求你 好么?
Please?
好的
Yes.
暂时不会走
For a while.
你看这个怎么样?
What do you think?
很漂亮 Jacob
It's very nice, Jacob.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
我只是有些累了
I'm just tired.
她知道你来看我吗?
She know you visit me?
她从来不问起你
She never asks about you.
那很遗憾 我问起了她
Then I'm sorry I asked about her.
你为什么来看我们 Jacob?
Why do you watch us, Jacob?
是因为 我想知道妈妈说得对不对
I watch because I wanna know if mother's right.
你说哪方面?
Right about what?
就是这些人
About them.
噢 你是说我的人
Oh, you mean my people.
你想知道他们是不是坏人
You wanna know if they're bad.
那女人大概疯了
That woman may be insane,
但这事她说对了
but she's most definitely right about that.
我不知道 他们好像对我还不错
I don't know. They don't seem so bad to me.
是啊 你不过是远观
Well, that's easy for you to say,
自然体会不深 但是相信我
looking down at us from above. Trust me.
我和他们生活有30年了
I've lived among them for 30 years.
他们贪婪 有控制欲 不值得信赖...
They're greedy, manipulative, untrustworthy...
而且 自私自利
and selfish.
那你为什么还和他们一起?
Then why are you with them?
因为我借助他们达到目的
They're a means to an end.
什么目的?
What end?
我要离开这里 Jacob
I'm leaving, Jacob.
- 我找到了离岛的方法 - 不 那是不可能的
- I found a way off the island. - No, it's impossible.
这个岛与世隔绝 无路可逃
There is no way off the island.
我的人中 不乏智者...
There are very smart men among us...
他们对金属为什么会被吸过去 很感兴趣
men who are curious about how things work.
于是我们一起 在岛上到处寻找
Together, we have discovered places all over this island
那些让金属发生奇怪反应的地方
where metal behaves strangely.
当我们找到一个这样的地方时
When we find one of these sites,
我们把它挖开了
we dig.
这一次 我们找到了些东西
And this time we found something.
跟我走吧 Jacob 走吧
Come with me, Jacob, please.
等她死了 你打算怎么办?
What are you gonna do when she dies?
她永远不会死的
She's never gonna die.
Jacob 任何东西都有消逝的一天
Jacob, everything dies.
我不想离开这座岛
Well I don't wanna leave this island.
这里是我的家
It's my home.
好吧 但这不是我家
Well, it's not mine.
你去哪了?
Where were you?
我去哪 你心知肚明
You know where I was.
他和你说了什么 Jacob?
What did he say to you, Jacob?
他说 他终于找到离开这座岛的方法了
He said he's finally found a way to leave the island.
可以和你聊聊吗?
May I join you?
好吧
Yes.
你还好吗?
How are you?
我很担忧
I'm worried.
妈妈 你是该担心
Well, mother, you should be.
我花了30年来找这个地方
I've spent 30 years searching for that place.
小时候 你带我去看过...
You brought me as a child...
那个... 会发出美丽光芒的瀑布
that... waterfall with that beautiful light.
我走遍了整座岛 从一端到另一端
I've walked this island from end to end,
但是 再没发现过那个地方
not once coming close to finding it.
后来我想到
But then I began to think,
要是那光埋藏在岛下呢...
what if the light underneath the island...
要是我可以从别的地方到那儿呢?
what if I could get to it from someplace else?
我花了很长时间 才找到去那儿的办法
Figuring out how to reach it took a very long time.
跟你在一起的那些人... 他们也看见了?
The people with you... they saw this, too?
对 他们想出了一些很有趣的点子
Yes. They have some very interesting ideas
来处理那道光
about what to do with it.
处理? 你根本就不知道...
Do with it? You don't have any idea wh...
我根本不知道 是因为你对我闭口不谈 母亲
I have no idea because you wouldn't tell me, mother.
这是什么?
What is that?
是个转轮
It's a wheel.
我们要弄个缺口...
We're going to make an opening...
一个比这个大得多的缺口
One much bigger than this one.
然后我要把那个转轮连到
And then I'm going to attach that wheel
我们正在建的一个系统上...
to a system we're building...
这个系统能够传输水和光
A system that channels the water and the light.
然后我要转动它
And then I'm going to turn it.
一旦我转动了它...
And when I do...
我就终于可以离开这座岛了
I'll finally be able to leave this place.
你怎么知道这些的? 你怎么知道这么做会成功?
How do you know all this? How do you know it will work?
我是特别的...
I'm special...
母亲
mother.
求你别这么做
Please don't do this.
别走
Don't go.
我必须得走
I have to go.
- 为什么? - 因为我不属于这里
- Why? - Because I don't belong here.
那么我想 这次是该道别了
Then I suppose this is good-bye.
再见 母亲
Good-bye, mother.
真的很对不起
I am so sorry.
啊!
Aah!
噢!
Uhh!
Jacob啊
Jacob.
是时候了
It's time.
出事了 是吗?
Something happened, didn't it?
是的 我不得不跟你的弟弟说再见
Yes. I had to say good-bye to your brother.
你要让他走?
You're letting him go?
我别无选择 这是他想要的
I don't have a choice. It's what he wants.
你记得这个地方吗?
Do you recognize this place?
记得
Yes.
你记得我在这儿给你看了什么吗?
Do you remember what I showed you here?
那道光
The light.
现在是你保护它的时候了
You're going to protect it now.
那下面有什么?
What's down there?
生 死
Life. Death.
重生
Rebirth.
这座岛的中心 便是这些
It's the source, the heart of the island.
答应我...
Just promise me...
无论如何 你永远都不会走进那里去
No matter what you do, you won't ever go down there.
进去会死吗?
Would I die?
会比死更糟 Jocab
It'd be worse than dying Jacob.
糟很多
Much worse.
给你
Here.
喝了它
Drink this.
我喝下去以后会怎么样?
What happens if I do?
你会承担起这份责任
You'll accept the responsibility
保护这个地方到最后
that you will protect this place for as long as you can.
之后你要去找你的接班人
And then you'll have to find your replacement.
我不想保护这个地方
I don't want to protect this place.
- 总要有人去做 - 我不在乎
- Someone has to. - I don't care.
- 我的时代结束了 - 为什么? 为什么你的时代结束了?
- My time is over. - Why? Why is your time over?
必须得是你 Jacob
It has to be you, Jacob.
不 不是的 你希望他来接替你
No, it doesn't. You wanted it to be him.
可是现在你身边只剩下我了
But now I'm all you have.
你一直都是最合适的人选 Jacob
It was always supposed to be you, Jacob.
我知道的 有一天 你也能找到最适合你的接班人
I see that now, and one day you'll see it, too,
但是在那之前...
but until then...
你无路可选
you don't really have a choice.
拜托
Please.
拿起杯子 喝了它
Take the cup and drink.
现在你和我...
Now you and I...
一样了
are the same.
暴风雨要来了
Storm comin'.
是的 要来了
Yes, there is.
你应该离开这儿 赶在下雨之前
You should go, get some firewood
找些生火用的木头
before it rains.
Jacob啊
Jacob?
小心点
Be careful.
咱们回家见
I'll see you back home.
你为什么不让我走 母亲?
Why wouldn't you let me leave, mother?
因为我... 我爱你
Because I... I love you.
谢谢
Thank you.
Jacob啊
Jacob.
你干了什么?
What'd you do?
等等 听我说
Wait. Listen.
- 你干了什么? - 不
- What did you do? - No.
你干了什么?! 你...
What did you do?! You have...
别 Jacob 别这样
Don't. Jacob, don't do this.
她把他们烧死了 她疯了
She burned them. She was crazy.
她把他们全都烧死了!
She burned them all!
你杀不了我 Jacob 她说过你杀不了我的
You can't kill me, Jacob. She made it that way.
你杀不了!
You can't!
别担心 弟弟 我不会杀你的
Don't worry, brother. I'm not going to kill you.
噢!
Uhh!
- 她带你回到这儿的? - 对
- She brought you back here? - Yes.
她要这么做?
Why would she?
因为我现在得保护这个地方了
Because I have to protect it now.
啊!
Aah!
你想找到这道光?
You want to find the light?
你想离开这里 是吗 弟弟?
You want to leave this place, brother?
那就去吧
Then go.
他们是什么人? 他们从哪儿来的?
Who are they? Where'd they come from?
- 你们几个 上周是不是杀了一只北极熊? - 对
- Didn't you guys shoot a polar bear last week? - Yeah.
它是从哪儿来的?
Where'd that come from?
嗨? 有人在吗?
Hello? Anybody there?
这些男人是谁?
Who were these men?
实际上 其中还有一个女人
Actually, one of them's female.
说得真像是亚当和夏娃
Our very own Adam and Eve.
再见 弟弟
Good bye, brother.
再见
Good-bye.